Jess Dowd

Wordpress | Web Developer

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | contactjessdowd@gmail.com | 1-573-309-8784 | MO, USA (remote)

Summary

Full-stack web developer proficient in Wordpress content management, JavaScript, React, PHP, HTML5, and CSS3, with a background in eCommerce and Education. Attended Practicum web Development bootcamp. Experienced building professional websites as lead developer and as part of a dev team while meeting deadlines. Recent experience includes working at a creative agency to build a new website for Pendulum Tudor/Rolex watches in Thailand, and a new website for a startup medical license company in California, Atreo.io

Technical Skills | Languages | Tools

JavaScript/JSX - React - Wordpress - PHP - HTML5 - CSS3 - CRA - SQL and jQuery - API - OOP - Algorithms - ContinuousIntegration (CI) - Data Structures- Deployment - Unit Testing - Webpack - Babel - JSON - SQL - DOM - Debugging - SCSS - Form validation - Git/GitHub - Figma - NPM flexbox - grid layout - BEM - Media queries - Bootstrap - Styled-Components - Thai (Basic, A2)

Technical Projects

Atreo - Wordpress - PHP - HTML - Bootstrap - 2022 atreo.io

Website using Wordpress and PHP with CSS3 bootstrap and custom animations with an adaptive layout.

- I was the sole developer and built this site with maintainable, reusable and functional UI components based on design
- Successfully implemented JSON API data to increase load speed
- Created a clean and user friendly backend and trained the client Atreo team on keeping the site content updated

Pendulum Rolex Boutique TH - PHP - CSS3 - JavaScript - 2022 pendulum.co.th/tudor

Website using Wordpress and PHP custom backend with CSS3 bootstrap and custom product listing with payment gateway

- Built maintainable, reusable and functional UI components using google maps API and product data with JSON, English and Thai
- Successfully implemented checkout and payment feature
- Created easy to navigate backend to update product listing with sorting and search features

Learning How to Learn - 2021 Website

Front-end App built with HTML and using CSS to create an attractive and interactive website on learning techniques

- Used CSS3 extensively to create seamless animation and hover effects
- Built reusable components using HTML, CSS, and BEM organizational methods

From Portland to Portland - 2020 Website

Front-end Application built with HTML and using CSS grid to display adaptive array of photos

- Used media queries to build a smooth UX/UI across all platforms (iPhone, Android, Tablet)
- Created pixel-perfect recreations of designer mock-ups from figma w

See More.....

Experience

InvisibleInk Creative Agency | Full Stack Developer Contractor | 11 /2021 - 02/2022

- Use Web Development expertise to build at lead dev using Wordpress
- Worked on-site in Bangkok Thailand with a team of developers and animators to create custom websites for clients.
- Built custom full stack websites from scratch communicated with clients to discus and create websites from design.

Certification Partners, LLC | SME Subject Matter Expert Contractor | 06/2021 - Current

- Use Web Design & Development expertise as an SME to evaluate and author material for CIW certification exams on advanced HTML5 & CSS3 web development.
- Work with CIW test development partner, Certiverse, to contribute to the Job Task Analysis(JTA phase) for Ecommerce Services Specialist and mobile application development exams.

Freelance | Web Developer | 01/2021 - 06/2021 - URL Shortener | Portfolio demo

- Developed a URL shortener demo using HTML and CSS and JS forfrontend, connected with backend API.
- Worked with a team to design and build portfolio websites using technologies CSS, HTML, GitHub, GitBash, Jquery.

Education

Practicum by Yandex | Intensive Web Development bootcamp program | 2020-2021

- Completed 10 projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and industry best practice standards for clean code.
- Worked on two week long sprints in an agile environment and participated in code reviews with senior developers.
- Project-based. The curriculum provides a wide range of projects based on Full Stack Development technologies.